CV Floor van Donkelaar

# Floor van Donkelaar

Email: floor.vandonkelaar@uzh.ch Website: fvandonkelaar.github.io ORCID: 0000-0002-7235-9747

Department of Astrophysics, University of Zurich

Main research interests: the formation and evolution of galactic structures in Milky Way analogues at high redshift and their interactions with stellar clusters through (cosmological) simulations.

### Personal Information

Nationality Dutch Date of Birth July 1 1998

Languages Dutch (Native), English (Fluent), German (Elementary), Swedish (Elementary)

## Education

MSc in Astrophysics
Aug 2019 - May 2021
Lund University, Sweden
GPA: 3.83/4.00

Thesis: The fate of stars born in gas-rich high redshift galaxies

Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Oscar Agertz

#### BSc in sociotechnical engineering, minor in modern physics

Sep 2016 - Jul 2019 GPA: 3.85/4.00

University of Twente (ATLAS), The Netherlands

Thesis: The Star Formation Rate, Metallicity and Thermal Pressure in Galaxies at z=0.4 using MUSE

Supervisor: Dr. Kasper Borello Schmidt from Leibzin-Institut für Astrophysik Potsdam

# Research Experience

#### University of Zurich

PhD student Sep 2021 – Present

Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Lucio Mayer

- · Research on the formation of disc galaxies investigating the gasues halos with the high resolution cosmological simulation, Phoebos, to be used in combination with observations of SKA.
- · Research on the formation of galaxy structures with GIGAERIS, a cosmological, N-body hydrodynamical zoom-in simulation of the formation of a Milky Way-sized galaxy.

#### Oxford University

Research Internship

Jun 2020 – Nov 2020

Supervisor: Dr. Kearn Grisdale

Analyzing gas and stellar properties of Giant Molecular Clouds in Large Magellanic Cloud-size disc galaxy with the use of N-body hydrodynamical simulations.

#### Leibniz-Institut für Astrophysik Potsdam

Summer Project Jul 2017

Supervisor: Dr. Kasper Borello Schmidt

Generating template spectra of MUSE-Wide emission lines sources.

CV Floor van Donkelaar

## References

Prof. Dr. Lucio Mayer, University of Zurich, lucio.mayer@uzh.ch Prof. Dr. Oscar Agertz, Lund University, oscar.agertz@astro.lu.se

## Teaching & Public Outreach

### supervising Master student(s), University of Zurich

Aug 2024 - Present

Supervisor for the semester thesis of ETH student Daniel Swingler, on the topic of star forming gas cloud properties at high redshift.

### Teaching Assistant, University of Zurich

AST 245: Computational Astrophysics	Fall 2024
AST 202: The Universe: Contents, Origin, Evolution and Future	Spring 2024
AST 245: Computational Astrophysics	Fall 2023
AST 295: Astrobiology proseminar	Fall 2023
AST 248: The Sun and Planets	Spring 2023
AST 295: Astrobiology proseminar	Fall 2022
AST 202: The Universe: Contents, Origin, Evolution and Future	Spring 2022
AST 201: Introduction to Astrobiology	Fall 2021

#### Chief Public Relations, Green Team Twente

Jun 2017 - Sep 2018

Student team working on one of the most efficient hydrogen city cars in world. As head of the public relations and graphic designer of the team, it was my main responsibility to decide about the appearance of the team and organ zine the main events.

### Invited Talks

A full list of the talks I have given can be found on my website.

- 'The Milky Way's nuclear star cluster' ISSI (Bern), 30 Aug 2023
- 'Stellar Systems at z > 4: The hybrid formation scenario for the nuclear star cluster' Lund University, 8 May 2023
- $\bullet$  'Stellar Systems at z > 4: Proto-Globular Cluster properties and the imposter amongst us' Lund University, 16 Nov 2022
- 'Disc formation and Globular Cluster analogs in the high resolution GigaEris simulation' ISSI (Bern), 31 Aug 2022

### Publication overview

Number of (first-author) publications:	3 (3)
Number of (first-author) submissions:	2 (2)
Sum of times cited:	33

CV Floor van Donkelaar

## Skills

Programming Python | MATLAB | SQL | C | C++

Other LaTeX | Windows OS | Linux OS | Microsoft Office Package | Adobe Package

## Active scientific member

Member of the HI Galaxy Science working group of SKA & part of SKACH.

# Organizations

• Public Relations Responsible
of the Grasshopper Club Zürich Rugby women's team

• PhD Representative May 2022 - Sep 2024 At the Institute of Computational Sciences

• UCT Alumni Association
Chair & PR representative

Sep 2021 - Aug 2022

• Faculty Council EEMCS Sep 2017 - Aug 2018 Elected member, University of Twente